My thesis is that crypto has been in a
bare market. I think that now we are
going into crypto's first real bull
market. It's the world's biggest casino
having a baby with the world's biggest
social network. I said all asset markets
will be 24/7 365. It'll be 100 billion
agents trading at a frequency that you
can't even imagine. It was like it was
built for the machines.
>> I think we now have the most exciting
opportunity in the world.
Token 2049 Singapore, the world's
largest crypto event, returns to Marina
Bay [music] Sands on the 7th of 8th of
October. On stage will be myself, Jeff
Yan from Hyperlquid, Shane Copam from
Poly Market, [music] and the Real Vision
community gets 10% off tickets. Claim
yours using the link below. See you
there. So, quickly before we get to
today's show, this episode is brought to
you by Pith. Piff Network is the fastest
growing financial data [music] company
today. Trusted by Fidelity Investments,
the US Department of Commerce, Revolute,
Calshi, [music] Jane Street, Coinbase,
and many more. They provide realtime
financial market data across over 3,000
equities, [music] commodities, crypto,
FX rates, and again a lot more. They're
the first and largest provider of 24/7
financial indices and offer the widest
array of market data for the lowest
cost. So go to pith.network network to
take advantage of their free trial.
>> Join me, Ral Pal, as I go on a journey
of discovery through the macro, crypto,
and exponential age landscapes. In the
journey, man, I talk to the smartest
people in the world so we can all become
smarter [music] together.
Ram, good to see you, my friend.
>> Nice to see you again, Ral.
>> I know. I was just I was just with you
the other way round yesterday and uh and
then we got you here today. It's been a
while since you've been on.
>> You had a you had a great chat
yesterday. It really inspired me. I
actually made a show about our chat
yesterday before I release the actual
show of the chat.
>> So there's no pressure on you now. You
you've got to be interesting, charming,
good-looking, all the things that I did
for you. You have to now do that for me.
>> You know, it's so funny because we clip
all our shows and we try and find the
best clippable moments for every show.
So, usually I get the clips file for a
normal guest. I get the clip file and
it's like, you know, five or six clips.
I got your clip file today. Well, it's
like 40 videos. It's like 40 little
clips of these. And each one of them is
a pearler. Each one of them like I
listen to till the end and I listen to
till the end.
>> It's not going to get me into trouble
though, is it?
>> No, not this time around. We're not late
enough in the bull market to get into
trouble. It's It's still early.
>> That's [laughter] true. That's true.
It's like the psychology of these
markets is ridiculous. How do you deal
with it? Because having the audience, I
mean, personally, we, you know, we're
sort of used to it now. We've all gone
through the ups and downs as we talked
about last time you were on, but it's
it's just like taking a whole audience's
emotions on your shoulders is not easy.
>> So, you got to have a a really really
thick skin and you got to have a lot of
conviction in your thesis. In the first
cycle, I took it really personally, but
I also did like some slightly I would
say less than responsible things. So
things that are completely normal for a
normal person. Um if you're in the
public eye are seen to be irresponsible
like you say, "Hey, I'm buying this."
And the truth is you are buying it. But
the fact that you don't say, "Hey, I'm
buying a little bit of this or I'm
buying this as part of a balanced
portfolio or something like that." So
you learn to be a little bit more
responsible. And then um you also learn
not to give a [ __ ] you you learn that,
you know, you have an opinion and you
you don't need to be apologetic for your
opinion. Um my as long as your opinion
is well researched. I think the one
thing I've done pretty well over the
years is I've learned to have a very
wellressearched opinion. So if I if I
reflect on my life of what I do every
single day, I'm surrounded by a team of
researchers and I probably have about 10
of I think amongst the best researchers
in crypto and all day long we just
research and talk about crypto. We make
portfolio moves along the way and then
what we do is like every day we switch
on the camera and I literally tell
people everything that I've learned in
the day and what the portfolio moves
that I've made for that day is. So it
becomes almost like a reality show
>> uh where I teach everything that I've
learned every single day and I'm not
learning on my own. I'm now learning
with a bunch of really incredible people
and now there's an added dimension where
the really incredible people have got
claude and and and chat GPT and that
makes the the our level of learning has
been absolutely exponential. It's like I
cannot believe how dumb we were a year
ago and how smart we're getting now. And
I I know I know it's just the beginning,
but
>> do you think we end up with an edge or
are we on a hamster wheel of having to
do more and more and more? That's kind
of I'm not sure about it. I think there
is an edge by being an early adopter,
>> but everybody has access to this. It's
insane.
>> So for me, for me, one of the the the
ways that I the only way that I know
that I have an edge is is is the the net
asset value. So let's just call it the
the portfolio size.
>> Your P&L is what it is.
>> Well, yeah. So I so we have a from for
me I index it as a net asset value. Um
and when I say net asset value
specifically in the crypto world and to
be honest the highest point of my net
asset value in crypto was in at the end
of 2024. It was that peak bull market
2024 and ever since then it's been low
and actually to be honest in my opinion
we're very very very early in a crypto
bull market and my net asset value in
crypto is the highest that it's ever
been. So it just means that we've
selected the correct tokens in in this
in this beginning or this or the bare
market which now beca became the
beginning of the bull market and then I
asked myself okay how did we do it so I
mean I think the one way we did it is we
really have our finger on the pulse uh
and we know like we know we know the
patient's heartbeat so we know when when
you know when the heartbeat's out of
sync we know what it is and we know if
that's an opportunity or or danger to
get out. I also think that we have a
we've had a great thesis for the cycle
and I think our thesis is really playing
out and then I think to be honest AI
tools like we really use a lot of AI
tools. A lot of our research is done
using AI tools and we can you know
because of that we can find we can find
runners. I'll give you like one very
simple example. When Robin Hood chain
launched we ran a whole lot of AI models
to tell us which who could benefit and
who could lose. Like just very basic
things of like who could benefit and who
could lose. And we found one sitting one
sitting duck which was arbitum. Arbitum
for those people who don't know is the
technology that Robin Hood chain is
built with. And they get 10% of Robin
Hood's revenue. And using AI we kind of
picked up what their revenues would be
and we translated that back into a
buyback program and then a price and we
we had a lot of conviction in that
trade. Now without AI to be honest I
think there's probably a 10% chance we
would have picked up that trade. with
AI, it became like a really obvious
trade because we knew exactly what we
were looking for. We knew what the
prompt was. We gave it a universe of
things to check and and you know, and
that gave us uh that gave us an unfair
advantage. So I think that AI, if you're
not using AI today in in the crypto
environment to do your research, then I
think to be honest, I think you're
falling really far behind. So I'm going
to go through this in detail but let's
because I think this is really
interesting for people but let's start
at the top is what is your thesis?
What is my thesis? So my thesis is that
uh crypto has been in a bare market. Um
I'm not sure what the cause of the bare
market was but it doesn't really matter
what the cause of the bare market was. I
think that now we're going into crypto's
first real bull market. Now, I know
people may say, well, how can you say
that 2017 was a bull market and 2021 was
a bull market? Actually, I don't think
they were. Um, I think calling 2021 a
bull market is the same as calling uh
1998, 1999 a bull market for internet
stocks. And to be honest, I don't really
think that you can call that a bull
market for internet stocks because there
was not a single internet stock actually
being used. There was no real use cases
for the internet. It was just a bull
market on the promise of big things to
come. And I think that if you think
about crypto, we've had a bull market in
2017. Um, in fact, I think I think if we
if we go I think the best way to look at
this is to actually call up a chart or
to to to call up a few charts. And
actually, let me call up one or two
charts just to to paint it for you. So,
for me, the the charts just tell a
story, right? So, I mean, that's the
Bitcoin chart. Everybody knows the
Bitcoin chart. You know, you had 2017
bull market, then you had a long bare
market, then you had um uh 2021, you had
the bull market, then you had a bare
market, and then you had this last bull
market, and now we've just had a bare
market, and it looks like we're out of
the bare market, and we're going into a
bull market on Bitcoin. I think
Bitcoin's relatively exciting to be
honest. I think, you know, when you
think about the debasement trade and all
the macro stuff, I think Bitcoin's,
yeah, it's relatively exciting, but to
be honest, I think this is crypto's
first real uh bull market. Now, I'll
show it to you in two in two different
charts, and I think you'll really
understand these charts, right? So, the
first chart is um is this chart over
here, which is the ETH BTC chart. So
this is the this is the chart of
Ethereum versus Bitcoin and I think it
tells a story and I think let's use
Ethereum as a proxy for all major
>> I can't believe you don't use log
charts. This is driving me
>> I do I actually I actually do but for
this but for this let me
>> I use the log chart on this.
>> Yeah. So for me this is this is ETH BTC.
>> Yeah. Um, for all intents and purposes,
let's call this all use cases for crypto
that are not stable store of value
money. So, all let's just call this a
proxy for all all use crypto.
>> All smart contracts.
>> Yeah. All use cases because that's
really all the use cases for crypto,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, what we can see is we launched in
2016 2017. We had the whole ICO boom
that failed because that use case wasn't
a real use case at the time. We had
another big push in 2020 2021 which was
the DeFi summer and again that was
rejected and went down because it wasn't
a real use case. It was too slow, too
expensive. The yield wasn't actually
real yield. It wasn't sustainable yield.
So that that market actually collapsed.
And then you kind of look at this and
you say 9 years later, 9 years after the
first use case of blockchain was created
other other than smart money which was
smart contracts, we've had a little bit
of a breakout in this chart. This is on
the ETHBTC chart. Now, what does that
tell you? It means that after 9 years,
there's a product market fit that
actually makes this chart break out or
there are multiple product market fits
that actually make this chart actually
break out. Right? So, for 9 years, we
didn't actually have a use case. We we
experimented, we rejected, we had a
second experiment that was rejected, and
now finally we're breaking out. The next
chart that I look at is this chart over
here. And this chart over here is others
versus B. Quite funny. I look at all of
these charts myself. This is exactly
what I'm doing.
>> Yeah. So, so this is exactly this is
exactly what what I'm looking at. Others
against um BTCUSD,
which is So that's the chart. This is
the top altcoins. And I actually want to
make this chart smaller because this is
where the whole thesis actually comes
together. Right. So,
>> and you're still not using a log chart.
I mean, you're such a rebel. You're such
a rebel.
>> Okay. So, others the top old coins
excluding uh the top 10. So this is a
smaller altcoins against BTC again. 2017
massive move up rejected no real use
case ICOs uh let's call it shitcoins etc
etc rejected 2021 DeFi DeFi summer
decentralized finance the whole
application again rejected but
ultimately if you look at it against
Bitcoin there's an upward trend and that
upward trend basically says the use case
of this technology
all other uses except for Bitcoin is
getting slightly better against Bitcoin
Okay, now let's follow both of these
charts because I think this is where the
story actually comes together. And this
is you ask me about my thesis. My first
thesis is that this bull market is going
to be led by altcoins. So yeah, Bitcoin
is exciting. Maybe it'll do a 2x. Maybe
it'll do a 3x. Maybe it'll get to 250.
Maybe it'll get to 360. Who knows? And
to be honest, who actually cares? My big
thesis is that after 9 years, the ETH
chart has had a breakout at the exact
same time when the other altcoins
against BTC is bouncing off a trend line
and starting to move up. Now, let's just
say hypothetically that we follow this
pattern over here and we hypothetically
we go like this and we say that this
chart does this and I don't know
whatever it does along the way and
eventually we find ourselves over here.
Okay, that's pretty much how I see this
this cycle playing out. Okay. And now
it's not really that different from any
other cycle. If you look at that cycle,
what the altcoins did against Bitcoin
was a 9x return against Bitcoin. If you
look at this chart over here, at this
cycle over here, they did about a a se
6x. And if you kind of take it from here
to here, it's about a 6x. So it's not
like abnormal, but the numbers are are
much bigger.
So then you say to yourself, hold on a
second.
What would cause this to happen? What
would cause the altcoins to outperform
Bitcoin by such a big by by 6x on such a
big number? And it actually comes from
this chart over here. And what this
chart is telling you is that crypto
after 9 years has found product market
fit. And I think that there's two places
where crypto has found product market
fit. One is exciting and the other one
is I mean much bigger than exciting.
It's something we can't comprehend. So I
think maybe let's start off with with
the the use case that's actually
exciting, right? Um I think the use case
that's actually exciting is the first
breakout here and that is the
tokenization of everything. So yeah,
everything is getting tokenized. Stocks,
bonds, commodities, everything is
getting tokenized getting put onto chain
and that's relatively exciting. Yeah,
because that in in the end, you know, we
built excess capacity of block space and
now finally we're going to fill that
block space with a lot of stuff.
>> So I think that when I when I joined
crypto and I joined crypto in 2014,
I think crypto was a solution without a
problem. And the the reason why I say
that is because it was always like why
do you need a token for that? The the
big question when when I came into
crypto was you don't need a token for
that. you don't need and everything we
said was you don't need a token for that
and everyone like said like like treated
tokens if they were a bad thing today I
think as you wrote in one of your uh
essays everything is going to be a token
because it's a single use case a single
use case token so we're now tokenizing
everything and putting everything onto
chain and everything becomes tradable so
computing power all of a sudden becomes
tradable um uh uh assets stocks become
tradable commodities ities become
tradable and they all become tradable on
chain. But the one use case that crypto
has found which I don't think anybody
realizes yet is a combination of two
things. It's the world's biggest casino
having a baby with the world's biggest
social network. So imagine, I don't
know, the world's biggest social
network, Instagram, Twitter, having a
baby with the world's biggest casino.
Okay, that's the first use case that
that crypto has found. Why? If you think
about why um why people go to the
casino, the casino is a cheap dopamine
rush. You go there in your head, you
pretend that you know the reason why
you're drawing an extra card. When you
draw the extra card and it's a low card,
which is exactly the card you wanted. In
your head, you justify that you had a
thesis and you had a formula and that
you were right and therefore you're a
genius and that gives you a dopamine
hit. So now the formula to get dopamine
is actually quite a simple formula. You
have to have a motivation. You have to
do work. The work has to yield a result
and then you have to get some kind of
gratification.
And when that happens, you get a
dopamine hit. So now if you think about
what dopamine is, dopamine is probably
one of the world's most powerful drug
hormones. So it's the self- validation
hormone. It's the one that tells you
you're a genius and you're right. And
that's the the the first. So we go to
the casino. We we we're geniuses because
we knew exactly which card to you walk
out of the euphoric. The reason why you
walk out of the euphoric is you're so
full of dopamine because you've done the
work. You've put in you've put in the
work. Your work is right. You've got
self validation. It's it's incredible.
Social media networks have exactly the
same dopamine loop, right? The reason
why we like social media, we tweet
something, we've done the work, we think
about it, we do the work, we tweet, and
then we just watch the likes go up. And
that's the validation. Okay, so that's
great. There's no bigger validation
though than actually making money. So
when the P&L goes live and everybody
sees your P&L going live, very
important, your P&L goes up and
everybody sees your P&L go up. It's like
it's almost like your Twitter like
counter was your selfworth net worth
calculator. So what has crypto created?
It's created a world where you can trade
almost anything. When you trade it, not
only do you get social validation
because most transactions are
transparent and people can see exactly
what you're doing, which is why apps
like Pump Fun and FOMO are having such
big success, but also you keep getting
this dopamine hit because not only are
you making money and getting external
validation, you're getting the money
validation as well. Now, which social
network today has a validation which is
not only likes but actual net worth,
actual personal scoreboard,
right? It doesn't exist. Now, what
crypto has created, it's created the
ultimate
social network for trading, which has
never been a available before, right?
It's there's never we didn't have the
the rails or the infrastructure for the
social media, the social networking.
It's the most addictive thing in the
world. And I believe that most trading
that is not going to be done by AI
agents is actually going to be some kind
of social trading. And I think if you
look at apps like FOMO and Pump Fund,
they've got the F V1 of that.
>> And prediction markets will feed into
this as well.
>> It's a formula. You've got to do it's
not about guessing. You've got to do
work so you can justify to yourself why
you're a genius. You've got to get a
scoreboard, right? You got to and then
you got to get self validation. So the
validation if it comes from the outside
is a So how did I how did I stumble onto
this? in one of the bull markets. I went
on vacation and I went from being in a
crypto bull market to having to spend
having to spend time with my family in a
holiday type environment and the problem
is that nothing was happening on the
markets. It was a very quiet period on
the market and what I found was so so
what did I do? I got really bored and
then I started to learn a new language.
I started learning Arabic
for what? Okay. And then I realized that
what my body was craving, it was craving
the the motivation, achievement,
reward, right? And so I went and learned
a new language on vacation cuz I was I
was starved of dopamine. And then I
stumbled onto what's going on with us
here in crypto. Most the reason why
we're in crypto is actually because we
do research,
number goes up, we feel like we're
geniuses. It's it's a drug. It's a
hormone. It's a drag. That's It's a
>> And also, just so people are aware, the
reason why you also pick up on this
stuff is your background was
advertising. And correct. Advertising is
>> is behavior.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So, I used I used to do
this for a living. I used to monitor why
people make purchase decisions.
>> And I stumbled on crypto. The biggest
use case in crypto is is um is
validation and reward. And with crypto,
the reward the validation is transparent
and the reward is is monetary. There's
likes are great for social credibility,
but it's it's it's ethereal. It's not
real.
>> If you got if if your like meant a
dollar, it would be worth
>> Correct.
>> It would be good.
>> Correct. And now it does. And now it
does. If you look at apps like FOMO and
Pump Fun and whatever it is, they're the
most addictive things in the world,
right? Because
>> I'm going to ask you the obvious
question. Is is this a good thing?
>> I think that yes, I think it's it's a
very good thing. I think trading is
going to become a lot more transparent
and it's going to become a lot more
addictive. So if you think that that
trading is addictive now,
>> but 85% of all retail traders lose
money.
>> Yeah. But I mean yes, you can say that
you can say that but you can say the
same thing. You can say the same thing
in a stock market, right? In a bull
market, everyone makes money. In a bare
in the they don't last the bare market,
right? But I think that I think that all
trading is going to start all human
trading is going to become social
trading in some shape or form. So
because it's going to become more transp
everything everything's going to be on
chain. Therefore everything's going to
be more transparent. The results are
going to be published almost real time
which they're not currently published
almost real time. They published in
quarters. It's not going to be live yet
anymore. It's going to be it's going to
be if you think of what FOMO app is
today which is probably the biggest
dopamine engine I've ever seen. That's I
think what what human trading is going
to be like. So the first use case for
crypto in my opinion is tokenization of
everything. trading of everything 247 by
humans, but at the same time giving them
this magic combination of a casino and a
social network, which we've never had
before. We've never ever ever had
before. It's
>> Yeah, we have on the Real Vision
platform a very similar idea where you
post your trade ideas, people can vote
on them, you see the P&L, how it works,
leaderboards, all of that stuff, and it
works well.
>> Actually, I got to show you this. I got
to show you this because I'm not sure
that a lot of your viewers have seen it
because it's very, very, very DGEN. Um,
but let me actually uh
>> which one's this? FOMO.
>> FOMO. I don't know if if people actually
have seen the FOMO interface.
>> Yeah, I've not used I've not used it
actually. I've heard a lot about it, but
I haven't used it because I just don't
short-term trade. So, but it's
interesting to me.
>> The it is the most addictive thing that
you've ever seen in your life. The the
amount of dopamine that these guys have
have engineered is it's it's
>> behind it.
>> Uh, I actually interviewed them. It's uh
they were six people until not so long
ago. Look, I'm not doing a shill for
their product because, you know, let
them do the shill for their product.
That is FOMO. And I just want to show
you how this thing is engineered for
dopamine. Every single one of those
badges is when people have bought. Okay.
So, you know, on every token,
>> we have exactly the same on Real Vision,
by the way.
>> You have a leaderboard.
>> And where people buy it. We've got the
same on Real Vision.
>> Yeah. So, there's a leaderboard here of
of who's made Avi Felman's made $383,000
today or whatever else. Um, for every
token you can see who the big buyers
are. Uh, for this person, you can see
exactly what his entire portfolio looks
like. So, it's completely transparent
and it is a dopamine machine. The
alerts, the feed cannot, it's much more
addictive on an app. It's made for to be
app first, not desktop first. But
there's a feed here of every trade
that's get taken by big people, by small
people, etc., etc. It's the ultimate
dopamine machine. Now, what I think is
going to happen is ultimately most
trading is going to be a derivative of
that platform and it's going to be about
dop it's going to be a social
network/investment casino um which is
going to be the ultimate dopamine
machine and we're going to be able to
trade anything you want 24/7 in 365 and
you can only do that uh glo globally you
can only do that on blockchain roles. I
mean that's that's the first use case
that that crypto has found. That use
case in my opinion doesn't take us from
here all the way to to here. And I mean
just to give you an idea, a quantum here
of the numbers here. If Bitcoin goes to
4 trillion and this goes seven times,
we're talking about a $32 trillion
market cap, which is about I mean, I'm
not sure what the market cap is today,
but you're talking about a 10 times
bigger market cap than we currently
have, right? So, how do we get the
market cap to be 10 times bigger than it
currently is? And then that's when we go
into the universe which I believe is not
even humans. It's it's the AI agent
narrative and I think we've spent a lot
of time actually discussing it. Funny
enough, um I want to show you something.
It's it's a discussion that I've had for
so long. But in the bare market, I was
really struggling to make content. I was
I was dying. I got to be honest. It was
a very very very brutal bare market
specifically for people like us who I
mean I make a daily show and I just want
to show you just quickly. I mean, you
you know this, but I think maybe the
audience aren't as as aware of of, you
know, as a content creator, specifically
what I do, I make daily shows. I make
them five or six days a week. And if you
look at what happened in this bare
market, it was it was a really
demotivating bare market. From the from
10:10, it was just down and down and
down. It was bad news after bad news
after bad news, which is great. But then
we had a period from February
>> of nothing
>> to August where Bitcoin was in a range
of between 60 and 70,000.
Nothing happened. And we were making
content every single day. And when I got
to about here, which is the end of July,
I got to break point where I gave up.
No, I didn't give up. I was going to
give up on the It's the closest I've
ever been to giving up on crypto. When I
say giving up, holding my investments
and not making my whole life about
crypto. And then at that point, and I'm
talking about like this was probably the
low point of my career. This is like the
I'd been battered all the way down here.
My community had been battered. People
hated crypto. People hated us because we
were in crypto. The stock market to make
it worse, the stock markets were
running.
>> Yeah.
>> This this bare market was extremely bad
because the stock markets were giving
people outsiz returns. Um
no, they're giving them AI type returns.
the Cosby was doing 5xes and crypto was
going down and down and down and down
and down and exactly at this point which
I think was probably the lowest point
that I've been in crypto. I actually
tweeted this and I said here's what I
don't think you're seeing and it was
more me tweeting to myself.
>> Yeah.
>> I said all asset markets will be 24/7
365. All markets will be settled
immediately on chain. Humans won't be
trading them. Instead, it'll be 100
billion agents trading at a frequency
that you can't even imagine. and all
those fees will be captured by crypto
protocols. And that tweet pretty much
kept me kept me in crypto. Like that
tweet and the thinking behind that tweet
kept me going right through to to pretty
much where we are today. For me,
>> I was the same at that point. I would
just zoom out and say what's actually
happening here. Every bank, every
financial institution has said they're
going to move on chain. Stable coins
have been shield by the Treasury
Secretary of the United States saying
it's going to be a three trillion dollar
market. And here's us lot going, "Oh,
crypto is going to be awful." I'm like,
it same as you is that the outcome has
to be asymmetric from here. Wildly
asymmetric.
>> Sometimes though, because you're so
close to the wood and I was very close
to the wood every day. You know, the
problem is that when you're doing a
daily show, when you're watching a
market daily, the move between 64 and
65,000 becomes a story and the move
between 65 and 66 becomes a story,
right? Because we're so close to the
wood. Most people look at 60,000 and
then they log back in at 70,000 and then
to them it makes a whole lot more sense.
But sometimes we're very, very close,
which is an advantage and a
disadvantage.
Anyway, now the thesis is is clearer
than ever. And you know, you ask me what
my thesis is. I think it's maybe
coincidental that today the Black Rockck
report came out and in that Black Rockck
report they basically confirmed I think
my thesis and your thesis. So for me the
thesis is that up until now the NASDAQ
has had a run and when I say the NASDAQ
the NASDAQ being a proxy for everything
that's AI.
>> Yeah.
>> And that run has been everyone building
infrastructure for what they believe
will be AI. Right. So you got, you know,
you got the data centers, you've got the
chip companies, you've got the energy
companies, you've got whatever it is.
And that NASDAQ run has pretty much been
everybody building the infrastructure
for AI. Great. So we've built the
infrastructure, we've got the Frontier
Labs, and what is this whole thing about
AI? AI is a bunch of agents. That's what
it is. Like everyone when they talk
about building out a the infrastructure
for AI, they're building the
infrastructure for a bunch of agents.
Fantastic. That's what drove the NASDAQ
vertically. That's what drove the Cosby
vertical. That's what drove world
markets vertical. Great. They built the
infrastructure for AI. They built the
infrastructure for a bunch of agents. So
that the agents could do what?
So that the agents could transact.
Great. So they built the infrastructure
so you could have all these agents who
eventually transact. And I kept asking
myself who is going to be the benefactor
of the transactions and I tried to con I
mean I convinced myself that it was
blockchain why because agents are going
to meet on the internet wherever they
meet they meet in I don't know I don't
even what you call it and they transact
and their transactions have to be they
trustless because they don't my agent
and your agent don't know who the owner
of the agent is. It's got to be
immediate settlement because if I want
to make an API call, you've got to let
me call that API, get the data, and pay
you absolutely immediately. It's got to
be so it's got to be trustless and it's
got to be immediate. Um, and I kept
saying to myself that the only way that
I can see this happening is blockchain
rails. But I kept asking wherever I
went, wherever I went, I kept asking
people, how are these transactions going
to happen? Because I needed someone to
say to me, it's not going to happen on
block on blockchain rails. Even like
last week when I was in New York, I went
to one of the big summits and I asked
people, I said I asked one of the big
developers, I said, "Please tell me my
thesis is wrong. Tell me that these AI
agents aren't going to use blockchain
rails to conduct all their
transactions." And he says, "They're
not." And I said, "Well, what are they
going to use?" And he says, "Well, what
do you kids use when they do
transactions and you got to set limits
for them and they're not allowed to go
on certain websites? You give them a
prepaid debit card." And he says one
thesis is that AI agents will use some
kind of prepaid debit card with
limitations where they are allowed to
spend and not allowed to spend and stuff
like that.
And when he said that he said prepaid
debit card and I just thought no just a
bunch of smart contracts about where an
agent can spend and can't spend and what
the parameters
>> and a wallet pre-loaded
>> and a wallet and a wallet and some kind
of proof of identity if or or or credit
score if required.
And then I started to do research into
the number of agents. I was like, "Okay,
well, how big is the workforce in the
world today?" So the workforce in the
world today is 3.3 billion somewhere
around there. Let's just call it for
round numbers. They reckon there's going
to be I mean I think I saw a number
earlier today. I don't know if it's how
accurate it is, but it says here there's
going to be 1 billion transacting
deployed agents by 2029.
And
>> I would take the over on that number.
10 times.
>> 10 times. I would take the over.
>> But hold on. Get this. They're going to
be executing roughly 217 billion
transactions a day. Okay. So, take the
over, take the under. I would take the
over on it 100 times.
>> Well, we've just seen that Meta Muse
thing and they integrate it immediately
with Shopify, um, with PayPal, with
everybody. It's like, okay.
>> Yeah. And so, what are these agents
going to be doing? agents today we today
we know agents as I give you a question
you give me an answer I give you a task
you give me the solution but the new
economy is actually every agent
interacting and paying each paying each
other a minuscule minuscule fee for the
service what's a service maybe it's an
API call maybe it's a data call maybe
it's maybe it's something we don't we
haven't even been able to work out yet
but it's little microtransactions and as
this says 217 billion of them per day
right now. Again, I've challenged myself
a million times to try and come up with
who the custodian that is going to be.
And this morning, Black Rockck published
a report and they basically confirmed
what I've been suspecting where they
basically said to actually quote them.
They said something here which which I
think was this is the buzz line here.
They said at the core of this
convergence, AI and digital assets both
arise from common foundations. Um so
they go to they they say the rise of
agentic AI and machine toachine payments
will likely increase demand for
blockchain rails. Existing rails such as
a and card network support substantial
automation although the onboarding
requirements and settlement economics
make them less suited to always on low
value transaction requiring programmable
execution. Basically in that line what
they said out with the old financial
system and in with with blockchain.
And that was like for me the cherry on
top where I made the show I actually
made the show today and I was like I've
been waiting for confirmation of my
thesis. I've known the thesis is right.
Everyone's been telling me that the
thesis is right but when you read a
report like that and Black Rockck
basically confirmed exactly what you've
said. I think we now have the biggest
the most exciting opportunity in the
world. And I actually woke up this
morning. I said like I I tweeted I said
we we we're in the most exciting
opportunity in the world. And again I'll
show it to you with a chart and this is
a really basic chart but it's just
showing you the purple line is is AI
returns. So AIQ returns the the uh the
other two lines are crypto returns you
know and they diverged on on 1010.
This was the infrastructure for all the
agents that eventually are going to do
payments using these rails. So up until
now you can say the infrastructure has
been built for all these agents. the
frontier models are building. You know,
if you've used Grockbot, I think
Grockbot is probably the best
representation because I've got like 10
10 bots inside my Grockbot. I mean, on
on on my on my I've got like 10 10
agents doing stuff and I know that
they're going to transact. And so, the
infrastructure that was built with this
chart
is was made for the transactions that
are going to be that are going to take
place on these charts.
And then from that point on it just
becomes I know for you it's a very very
broad selection. So for you I know it's
a you just want to own the very broad
rails but for me it actually goes into
which altcoins are going to benefit the
most. I want to get into that process.
So you've laid out your thesis which I
completely agree with. I wrote my whole
agent thesis about a year ago about all
of this. Um and it's it became so
[ __ ] obvious that this is almost the
purpose of blockchains. It was like it
was built for the machines.
>> Exactly.
>> So you see that we see the whole
financial system coming on board. We see
this rise of speculation. We see the
rise of prediction markets. We haven't
even started with identity. We haven't
even done any of the web 3 stuff yet
that still is going to come on chain in
time. So it's like, yeah, I I get that
too. I don't think there was a I don't
think that this was a full bare market
um in terms of the full cycle. I feel
like it was a midcycle and that like you
I think there's potentially a very very
a longer and more dramatic move to come.
>> I think you're talking about Bitcoin and
for Bitcoin to be honest I mean I don't
I say I don't really care. A lot of my
wealth is in Bitcoin. I'm very bullish
on Bitcoin the asset but you're
referring to Bitcoin bull markets and
Bitcoin bare markets. I don't think
crypto altcoins have had a market a bull
market yet.
>> No they haven't because even ETH has
been in that bloody triangle that that
wedge pattern for five six years now. So
I I agree.
>> Let's define a bull market not as prices
go up. Let's define a bull market as
companies and protocols actually make
revenue. So I mean you know you can
define the 2000 bull market around an
internet bull market. In my in my eyes
that wasn't a real internet bull market.
It was the promise of the internet bull
market. And I think with crypto we've
had the promise of the of the of the in
the promise of the crypto bull market.
But I think now we've actually got
protocols that are making a million,2
million, $3 million a day in bare
markets. And you know, you take like
Pump Fun, which is I mean Pump Fun is
the most ridiculous protocol to for
people to launch memecoins. And they're
making between$1 and $5 million a day,
depending on the day. Okay. Now you're
starting to talk about crypto protocols
that are actually making real money,
right? Um Hyperlquid, you know, making
it's hard to say, but 5 million a day, 4
million a day, 3 million a day,
depending depending on the day. So you
finally got real use cases that are
actually working in crypto that are
generating revenue. And so I think that
this is crypto's first real bull market.
And again, you can say a bull market,
prices going up, but I'm going to I'm
saying prices going up, technology being
used, revenue actually being generated.
That that is for me a bull market.
>> What's hilarious is it's almost like a
record low for VC investment because
everyone gave up on the applications
layer and the applications layer's come
through. We've had some really big use
cases whether it's Poly Market, whether
it's FOMO, whether it's Hyperlquid,
whether it's, you know, we're seeing an
applications layer being built. Okay, I
want to move on to the next bit. So,
we've got the the uh the thesis. Now,
you talked about the process around the
research.
So, now you're trying to find the
opportunity set within the thesis. So,
talk me through how you do that. So, a
quick break in your regular programming.
If you're serious about your future,
grab my free report called Prepare for
2030. I think you've got five years to
make as much money as possible. And this
guide will help you navigate what's
coming. The link is in the description.
Download it now. So, first of all, yeah,
I I say this is I think where where my
investment style and your investment
style diverge. Why? Because I'm I'm
you're much more macro and you're
playing much bigger macro trends and I'm
looking for the the the opportunities
inside. So the first thing is to me you
you got to ask yourself
when is a token valuable? And the answer
of when a token is valuable is it's got
to have network effects. And for those
people who don't know what network
effects are even though I'm sure that
everybody at at Real Vision must know
what network effects are because I think
you're probably one of the first people
that taught me about network effects.
But every user has to add value to the
network exponentially.
Now
tokens become valuable when there is a
network and there scarcity. So so the
fact that there's a network is great but
if there's no if there's a network but
no scarcity and tokens can be minted
forever and the token supply is growing
as fast as a network it doesn't really
matter. It only matters when there's
scarcity. So the first thing is I look
at the first thing is is there a network
and again let's talk about hyperlid. Is
hyperlquid a network? Yes. Why? Because
every user adds liquidity to the network
and therefore the more liquidity you
have, the more people are going to trade
on that network, right? The quicker you
can get in and the quicker you can get
out with the least slippage and and um
and the the broadest range of positions
that is a liquidity is a network.
Trading is a network. So the first
question becomes then um is it a
network? Is the network actually
growing? So yes, you could have network
style tokconomics, but is the network
actually growing? So once it's a network
and the network is growing, you say, do
they have real revenue?
Yes. Great. Then you then you ask one
last question. And the last question is,
do they have one second last question,
do they have a mechanism to transfer the
value back to the token holders?
If the answer to that is yes, great. But
be careful. If the answer to that is no,
probably the best token opportunity that
you've ever seen. So, let me explain to
you what I mean. There's a network. The
network's making revenue and they find
and they find a way to reward the users
for the value. Everyone knows the value
of the network, right? Because all they
do is they forecast the rate of growth
of users. They forecast the revenue and
they forecast how much of the token
everyone's going to buy back and burn.
Example, Hyperlquid. They buy everyone's
now forecast that Hyperlquid is going to
buy back and burn three, four, $5
million a day depending on the market
forecast. They divide that by the number
of tokens in circulation and therefore
they get a metric for for for the value
of hyperlquid and we'll talk about the
metric in a second.
If they don't yet have a mechanism to
return value to the users currently
those are the most undervalued tokens.
So in crypto the terminology is do they
have a fee switch? FE switch means a
switch that returns the fees back to the
users. So right now those are the best
opportunities in crypto protocols that
are networks growing in users making
money but haven't yet determined how
they're going to give money back to the
users. So if you forecast and you say I
believe that they're going to give 50%
of their revenue back to the users and
you've got a smart way of forecasting
how they're going to give revenue back
to the users then you have an edge. So,
what are my the best tokens that I've
that I've bought are
I bought a token recently called uh
collector crypt. It's called cards.
Essentially, in a nutshell, what they do
is they take Pokémon cards, they put
them into a vault, a real world vault,
and they give you a token representation
of the Pokemon card. Okay? Now, you may
think that that's nothing, but a tok
Pokemon card is a real world asset. And
the token is a representation of the
real world asset on chain which allows
people to trade. I'm giving you a very
simplistic representation of what they
do. Right now the velocity of the
trading becomes 100 100x what it is.
They're acrewing 100x more fees than if
people were actually trading physical
Pokémon cards. Now they haven't yet
worked out how they're going to re to
pass that back to the user. And the
reason is because there's no SEC clarity
yet of what they're allowed to do and
what they're not allowed to do. best
opportunity in the world because people
haven't factored in that they're going
to give the fees back to the users.
That's an opportunity. So the first so
so so do they have you is it a network?
Is the network growing? Is there real
revenue? And then is there a way to give
revenue back to users?
That's the first class of tokens.
The problem with tokens is though that
people value tokens like and this is
what I'm working on right now which we
by the way we haven't cracked yet but
I'll I'll walk you through how we're
thinking about it. So the f the only way
that you and I know how to value assets
companies revenue generating assets is
you take the revenue they make and you
multiply it by a multiple and divide it
by the number of shares that they have.
That is how you value a share right? to
say what are the total number of shares
times that by the share price that's the
fully diluted value of a company right
>> mhm
>> great so everyone takes that valuation
into crypto and they say well you know
if there's a billion tokens outstanding
right and the value of the token is $3
that means that the fully diluted
valuation of the protocol is $3 billion
mistake and that's one of the biggest
mistakes that people make in crypto
because they don't understand crypto
right
you compare Coinbase to Hyperlquid Okay,
Coinbase has I just want I don't want to
mislead the user. So, let me actually
give you the number here. And this is
what I'm spending probably 80% of my
days doing right now because I know if I
crack this formula, the price is huge.
So, Coinbase have a market cap of 52.4
billion. Which means that if you take
the number of shares times the share
price, the value is 52.4 $52 billion.
>> Yeah.
>> Hyperlquid. So, this is Hyperlquid. They
have a $20 billion market cap, but an 89
billion fully diluted. So, if you take
all their tokens times the price, it
it'll give you 89 billion, but there's
only a 20 billion market cap. Now, this
is what where people get things wrong.
They take a valuation of a share and
they try and import that to crypto.
There's a fundamental difference. When
you have a share, all the shares or most
of the shares are tradable in the market
and there's a price. With crypto, it's
not like that.
Firstly, a lot of the the tokens may not
be in the market because
programmatically they're not in the
market, right? Like if you think about
Bitcoin, there's still a million Bitcoin
that that aren't in the market. The
second thing is that so so already
you've got the market becoming instead
of being that big, it's becoming that
big cuz these tokens aren't in
circulation yet. Then crypto's got this
thing called staking. What is staking?
staking says that if you want to launch
a token on Hyperlquid, you have to lock
away some of those tokens. So, it makes
the pipe even smaller.
>> Okay. So, and then you've got uh other
mechanism other mechanisms in crypto
which make the pipe even smaller.
Staking etc, etc. So, now what is the
the price? It's not the fully diluted
valuation. It's a function of this pipe.
the tighter and smaller the pipe and the
more
>> actual available supply versus the total
demand for the thing and the available
supply
>> pressure in the pipe. So with a stock
the price the pipe is this big there's
no way to make shares scarce. You you
never lock up shares to get benefits or
whatever else. So shares aren't scarce.
So the pipe's always this big and the
water's always flowing buying pressure
is always flowing through this pipe
>> unless they're doing buybacks like the
big tech.
>> Yeah. But buybacks is just the company
buying back its own tokens and never
burn. They don't buy back and burn. They
just buy back and keep it on the balance
sheet. Right now, let's talk about what
happens in crypto. Hyperlid has 90
billion dollars worth of shares. 70
billion aren't being emitted that aren't
being emitted for the next 10 years
programmatically. So, all of a sudden,
now the pipee's only 20 big of 20, uh,
you have to lock up $50 million worth of
Hyperlid to launch a token on
Hyperlquid. And you have to keep it
locked up and staked for as long as the
token's listed. Now, the pipe gets
really small. And then Hyperlid have
this thing called a buyback and burn
mechanism where they take a percentage
of their fees and create buying pressure
inside this pipe. So to me token
valuations are a function of the
pressure inside the pipe. So so what do
you have to work out? You have to work
out how how thin the pipe is and how
much buying pressure is going to be in
that pipe.
>> Sure.
>> And that's how you work out token
valuations at a at a at a certain point
in time.
>> Yeah. It is a function of the pressure
in the pipe and which which stocks don't
have because you never lock up stocks.
You never lock up stocks. You never
stake stocks etc. You you can't use your
stocks to participate in the
>> this is also one of the reasons why
crypto can be very volatile.
>> Yes. Because the liquidity is never
enough enough for the demand or the
supply. I in a bare market there's not
enough liquidity. the price it goes down
more because the free float is so small.
So in equities it's a free float. So the
free float in SpaceX is like 5% or 10%.
It's ridiculously small.
>> Um but yes,
>> but now but SpaceX doesn't have buying
pressure um uh uh u uh automated buying
pressure.
>> It does via the NASDAQ inclusion. It's
it once you put it into an index, you
kind of get all the 401k month money
every two weeks. The same will happen in
crypto when we create real indices. But
>> imagine with every with every space part
SpaceX part that was sold, they had to
buy back SpaceX shares. Then can you
imagine with a 5% free float what that
equation would look like?
>> Yeah.
>> And so and so you said to me, what am I
looking for all day? I'm looking for
pressure in pipes.
What's the scarcest token with the
highest buying pressure? Right? Because
everyone's valuing these protocols the
same way they value companies at
terminal point. And yes, Hyper Pilot is
valued at 90 billion at terminal point.
But today the pipe is only 20 billion
thick and there's buying pressure. And
so
>> that's basically what we're looking for
or right now what we're looking for.
We're looking to find networks which
have a lot of pressure in the pipe. Um
and if you can calculate the pressure in
the pipe correctly or better than
anybody else, then that's free money in
crypto at the moment.
>> Okay. You've talked about your research
process. So you mainly focus on these
kind of opportunities. So these tend to
be application layer higher velocity
low free float but still a reasonable
size not always. What size are you
looking at within these?
>> So I think um I think the layer one war
is largely one. So in crypto I think the
layer ones have largely been determined.
I think Bitcoin is the layer one for
store of value. I mean no surprise. I
think in terms of of the other layer
ones, I think it's a it's ETH and Solana
have basically won the war. When I say
ETH, I don't think ETH has won, but I
think the layer twos on ETH, the Robin
Hood chains, the the um uh base chains.
I think they're going to be the winners
because they've got the credibility of
settling on Ethereum and um and they've
got the speed they the speed and agility
of everything else they need. I think
there's two more use cases that need to
find a home. One of them is a very big
prize. The Agentic L1 hasn't been won
yet. Uh I think there's a couple of of
contenders in for that. I think SUI is
is definitely one of them because I
don't want to get too technical, but
it's an object-based language and an
object-based chain and that is much more
suitable for for AI transactions. Number
one, I think NIA protocol NIA is is
building a lot of a lot of tools. It
could be Salana. It could be base. So I
think the agentic L1 that war has still
to be won. I think the tradfi L1 when I
say tradfi I really mean traditional
finance L1 where are the dcc DTCC going
to migrate where are the the existing
clearing houses going to migrate to I
don't think that's been won yet there's
a whole lot of contenders in that race
but ultimately I think the L1 the block
space debate in crypto is pretty much
finished right I also think that the
L1's haven't found a way to really
capture value so if you're a ETH holder
guess how much value you captured from
the Robin Hood launch. And the Robin
Hood launch, just to give you some
numbers, in my opinion, was the most
perfectly executed launch that crypto
has ever seen. Robin Hood launched a
chain. The chain made $50 million in the
first two weeks in revenues for Robin
Hood. Guess how much of those fees ETH
managed to capture?
>> $50,000.
$50,000. So, I'm going to give you a
different way of valuing layer ones that
you should think about. If I were to
turn the plug off, the switch off on ETH
tomorrow, how much value gets destroyed
and future value? All of Robin Hood.
>> I agree with you.
>> All of base, all of DeFi, all of stable
coins, all of digital art, the whole
financial systems, future rails, the
whole lot. Now, that's a trillion, two
trillion. I don't know what the future
anticipated value of that is. And it's
nothing to do with fees. Fees are
irrelevant. They're a red herring. In
fact, in technology, fees are a
friction. And every technology that's
ever scaled, we've seen fees go to zero.
In blockchain, in order to keep the
lights on, you need people validating
transactions, right? You need a lot of
people validating transactions. In order
to do that, they need to be rewarded.
So, they get rewarded in one of two
ways. The first thing is token native
inflation. So that's a bad inflation. So
if there's token native inflation, it's
a bad inflation. It's the same as
government inflation because it means
the value of the network is being
deflated away.
Um the second way is fees. And by
increasing fees, you would penalize the
chain a lot. So let's talk about
Ethereum around your your thesis. um
it's either going to emit enough ETH to
keep a lights on and we're going to hope
that in perpetuity this can happen or
the fees have to be so high that the
miners have to be rewarded because the
more security in blockchain the more
validators you need. So security in
blockchain is a function to a certain to
a certain point of how many validators
you've got in the network, right? That's
the the strength of a blockchain. That's
why the Bitcoin network is so big. So
there is also the Bitcoin debate as you
know uh around what happens when Bitcoin
stops emitting coins. Now it's only
going to happen in 21 something, 2150,
2140 whatever it is, but what happens
then the fees have to basically fund the
network, right? And then you know maybe
they will, maybe they won't. We'll worry
about that in in 2150 if we're still
around. Um, but so I think the layer one
model in crypto right now, it's working,
but it's only working because it's
subsidized by token inflation at the
moment.
>> And you see, I again, I would dis I
disagree with this because
if we're right that the agentic economy
is coming, the velocity of everything
goes to the [ __ ] moon.
>> Agree. I agree. Then then Yeah. And if
you're charging 0.00001
cents for a trillion transactions, it
don't matter.
>> Agree.
>> You know, you can make a lot of money
from a very low transaction fee. I mean,
there was a great example yesterday. I
don't know if you saw um you might not
have seen it, but there was a a friend
of mine who's a uh digital artist, NFT
artist, Jack Butcher. He sold using the
X Money Network. First time this has
been done. So people on X money, so X,
>> he said, "Pay me 10 bucks and I'll give
you a piece of art."
>> He he made, I don't know, a million or$2
million yesterday from $8 art.
>> And then he's now got this buy back and
burn and complicated mechanism for it.
[ __ ] clever.
>> But low find it. Yeah.
>> Low low prices, high volumes. He sold
123,000
>> pieces of art. So
>> I agree with you. And I think the gent
economy is very, very, very, very soon.
Like I think people talk about I think
it's I think the genty economy is 2027
2028 2029. I don't think it's 2040. I
think as the the article here said it's
you know you're talking about a billion
agents by 2028 or 2029. It's that's it's
it's around the corner.
>> So so are all of your bets based around
this these these basic thesis? So I most
of them are looking for the low free
float where demand is.
>> So no I've taken my bets in the layer
ones. I've got my bets on the layer
ones. I've got my bets on Bitcoin. I've
got a little bit of money in Ethereum.
I've got money in Salana. I've got money
in Sui. I've got some small bets on
other ones. Near Protocol being one of
them.
>> And you just leave those.
>> Never touch those. Those are savings
accounts. The only time that I will
touch Salana example is if I will I may
take some chips off the main chain to
fund an application that I think is more
exciting than the main chain. But I'm
I'm drastically increasing my risk
profile then, right?
>> Yeah. Because if I bet on Salana, I'm
betting on a billion experiments that
may take place on Salana. If I'm betting
on one app, then I'm betting on.
>> And what is the percentage ratio between
your core holding and your active?
>> Are they 50/50 or are they 20 200? Which
way around?
>> So, it's a great question. Um, the
question is whether whether or not you
include Bitcoin. So, if you ex if you
include
>> No, include include Bitcoin. You see,
because Bitcoin is my store of wealth
and my store of value, then then you you
largely skewing it with L1's. But let's
remove Bitcoin. Yeah.
>> And then I'd say probably right now
>> I am,
>> see, I've had a great run on Zcash and I
haven't rebalanced my portfolio. So
probably right now I'm about 50 60 No,
probably about 60 70% in L1's, but only
because
>> because Zcash outperformed.
>> I took a a bet on Zcash at 100 bucks and
it's now six. It's 17 times that money.
>> Yeah.
>> And I haven't rotated yet because
>> because I look at Zcash and it reminds
me of Bitcoin 2014.
>> I've got some Zcash as well. I got in
about 300 bucks or something and it's
doing nicely.
>> Yeah,
>> it's it's exactly Bitcoin. It's the same
people. It's the same culture. It's the
same price moves. It's the same issues.
uh the the devs left and then the devs
came back and then and then you know
like and then they thought there was a
hack but actually there it's ex I heard
all these I've watched this video before
and I'm watching it again now you know
if there's one mistake I made on on
Bitcoin it's that I didn't accumulate
100,000 Bitcoin back in the day when I
you know I mean maybe 10,000 Bitcoin
when I actually could have afforded to
accumulate 10,000 Bitcoin, right? And I
kind of said to myself when I saw the
Zcash thing happen I said I'm not going
to make that mistake again. and I'm
going to get in early. I'm going to put
the money down and I'm going to forget
about the money. But my thesis
was sound as hell. And it was very very
very tough sitting through that thesis.
Two things happened. I don't know if you
remember but towards the end of last
year two things happened. The first
thing is the devs left. There was a big
announcement that devs left. They didn't
they just left one dev company and
started a new dev company. But that was
very scary and that tested the thesis.
And then the most important thing that
tested the thesis was around the
potential hack that could have happened.
Right.
>> That's right.
>> And that was that was really testing the
thesis because
>> Yeah. Because it was is there is there
now infinite supply and we don't know
because it's all hidden.
>> Yes. And that's the one that's the one
flaw that there was in Zcash. I say was
there isn't that four doesn't exist
anymore cuz with the new technology
upgrade they can actually verify that
what's in the shielded pool plus the
unshielded pool equals 21 million.
Before they couldn't all they could tell
you was in the unshielded pool the non
the non um uh shielded pool they could
tell you how many there were and how
many there should be in the shielded
pool but they they could never verify
what's in the shielded pool. Now they
can. So so now now they can. So, it's
made the thesis a lot more bulletproof.
Um, and I'll tell you that sitting
through that sitting through that period
where there could have been a
vulnerability in Zcash with a large part
of your portfolio in Zcash, like let's
say let's say that over 10% of my
portfolio was Zcash and sitting there
knowing that this comp the protocol
could have been compromised. I mean that
was th those were quite tough days
because again if they were compromised
Zcash could have gone too close to zero.
So it was a a uh you know you had to
hold with conviction. A lot of people
ran away a lot of people left. They said
you know I even remember with all due
respect to to Arthur as I remember
interviewing him at that period he said
you know the fact that this did happen
made me sell all my Zcash
>> and that's Arthur and that's Arthur. He
said he sold all his Zcash and he's not
I mean he's quite astute you know he he
knows the market and he said look that
dent so a lot of people left and I mean
we held and that's become a very big
part of the portfolio so um so I'd say
right now 60 70% is in L1's and then
okay so I don't consider hyperlquid an
L1 so hyperlquid no
>> is another big position
>> the competitor to hyper liquid called
lighter which is um uh the more
regulatory they went a more regulatory
friendly approach. Um, and the reason
why I took a big bet on lighter, just to
give you some some insight,
I knew that they were trying to get
Hyperlquid into the US and that there's
a negotiation going on with Hyperlquid
to bring Hyperlquid to the US.
>> Yeah,
>> I also know how Trump
>> it was Trump or Bessant who mentioned
Hyperlquid. It's insane. Trump. Trump
>> that was the that was when I doubled
down on lighter, ironically. And it's
been one of the best bets that I've made
because how does Trump negotiate? He
tells you how amazing your life's going
to be if you join him, right? He shows
you how miserable your life is going to
be if you don't do what he says. And
then somehow he and and then because you
realize how miserable the tariffs are
and because you realize so when he said
we're going to we bring in Hyperlquid
into the US I was like oh and what's
going to happen in the negotiation he's
going to threaten at some point Trump is
going to threaten Hyperlid with the fact
that they're not coming into the US
unless and then the market's going to
panic and they're going to go to the
next competitor which is lighter because
lighter has gone the more regulatory
route in the United States And that
switch I made when lighter was at about
$180 or something. I don't remember the
exact numbers. Lighter is now $550.
Hyper liquid was at about 80 or $70.
It's at 100 bucks. So that was a very
good switch to make. Um yeah. So
the majority So where else are my are my
bets? So
again, it goes down to the foundations
of what is crypto. What is crypto?
Crypto is the ability for anyone to
create digital value and trade digital
value. That's basically what crypto is.
Anyone can create or migrate digital you
can create digital value from a real
world asset. You can create it out of
thin air. You can create digital value
and if you can create digital value then
you're going to trade it because value
is there to be traded. So the majority
of my bets are actually on the trading
platforms.
Very very very few of my bets are in
non-trading platforms cuz I don't really
care what application you build whether
it's supercompute or whether you're
selling I don't know chip chips for
raceh horses I don't really care I know
you're going to trade it and I want to
be in the places where you traded and
the more leverage the better. Okay, so
let's wind ahead to two years time and
Ran's
thesis has paid off, but something else
came along that he didn't see because
there's always something new in a cycle
that you're like, "Fuck, I saw that, but
I didn't see it." What's it going to be?
Where is something going to break out in
this market that none of us are
expecting? Because it won't be what we
know always. It'll be something we don't
know.
What do you think? I mean, like for me,
the AI agent thing is so big and it's
just just just just just started and I
think learning their behaviors and their
trading and their hedging and their like
everything else um is just so big that
like it's it's enough to occupy
it's enough to occupy whatever we're
doing times 10. So, I must haven't
really thought like way beyond that. I
don't know because don't forget in the
past there were
>> there were what were social networks
going to do with blockchain? What were
we going to do with ID? What were we
going to do with
like data storage? You know, there's I
don't know there's just to me is I
always keep my eyes and ears open to
something that is entirely not on the
agenda today that some weirdo in a
somewhere has figured out. Um,
and let's see.
>> I like to go back to to core principles.
And for me, core principles is what what
is this technology. This technology is
about the creation of digital value.
When you have value, you're going to
let's well, you're going to store it.
I'm not sure that there's much money in
in the storage, right? You're going to
send it. Okay. Sending is probably the
money is probably in things like stable
coins, algorithmic stable coins,
partially backstable coins, fully
backstable coins. I'm not sure what that
application is. Um, you're going to
trade it. You're going to leverage it.
>> Yeah. But there's also other there's the
it's a database that is immutable
that has authentication built into it.
>> There is a whole bunch of parts of
blockchain that aren't currently used a
lot.
>> That's what that's it in my head.
>> So, I'll tell you one application which
I think is underused in crypto. Um,
what's the time where you are?
>> 208.
>> Why isn't it block 10642?
Why is it 208? Because humans have this
thing. Humans have this this thing of uh
of, you know, we need 24-hour days
because we need routine and the sun
rises and the sun sets. Agents don't
give a [ __ ]
>> No.
>> Agents for for agents, it's one long
number of blocks.
>> Yeah. Melton was talking about this
actually using the blockchain.
Well, yeah. So, I think the blockchain
clock has got to be the most accurate uh
the most accurate clock. It doesn't make
sense that we talk about dates and
times, EST, non EST. Ultimately, we need
to talk about about blocks. And I think
the one underused mechanism around
blockchains which I don't think anyone's
cracked yet and maybe we're very very
very early into this is like if if I
give you a loan um when when did I if I
give you a loan and I give you a loan on
one chain and it needs to be settled
somewhere else by another chain through
an AI agent and whatever else when did I
give you the loan and we're specifically
talking microp payments and micro micro
micro interest. When did I give you the
loan? So I think the one aspect of
blockchains that isn't yet respected
enough is the time aspect of it.
>> Yeah.
>> So so so like it it can't be a minute
and a second and an EST and a and a PST
>> in a daily in a dealing room. When I was
in a dealing room I'd write a ticket cuz
on a trade and I'd have to time stamp
it.
>> Yes.
>> Now we could change that by you time
stamp in advance. You do other stuff.
Right. But blockchain does something.
You're right with time
and price or time and information or
time and whatever that is it's yeah
you're it's completely underutilized
still.
>> So so I think I think
>> as a log of events let's put it that
way.
>> Yeah I think we I'm extrapolating a
couple of years forward but right now
the fastest blockchains have uh I don't
know 100 millisecond uh times to
finality
right. Um, and so their blocks are being
mined probably at that speed or maybe
slightly faster. I think that there's
going to be a lot of protocols that are
going to be measured in block in in
block time. And I think we're going to
come to a universal block time at some
point, which is like for example, like
you think about Bitcoin having to
transact with ETH and Salana and Suie
because that's just the way that the the
the transaction was settled, right?
When do they settle? And so ultimately I
think we're going to come up with a a
blockchain that's just going to be the
time. I I I I I think there's one or two
blockchains that were looking at this,
but I think one or two blockchains we're
going to pay them a minuscule fee just
to use them as a settlement layer for
multiple times.
>> Oracle for time
>> for time. The oracle for time. I think
that that that use case is probably
underappreciated specifically with
thousands and thousands thou thousands
of chains where where you know if if if
if microtransactions really matter and
you've got to settle them all at a
specific time in in micro seconds I
think the time element of blockchain is
is is uh is not well enough respected um
>> super interesting right final question
about all of this because you at the
beginning you stay said there was three
component parts of what you're doing and
how you're doing it one was your thesis
we've gone through that two
How are you valuing this stuff? Where
are you looking for opportunity? And
three is how are you using AI? So how
are you using AI and how's the team
using AI? Is that for building trading
models or is it for analysis or is it a
combination or is it for scraping for
information? Because people are
fascinated by this stuff.
>> So the first thing is we we automated
everything. So I realized I was running
a very very we running a very very uh
fat staff business in an age where most
things could have been automated. And so
I took what I did was I took the biggest
innovator of my team. She's amazing.
She's the biggest innovator in the team.
And I said if you want to innovate then
the first thing you're going to do is
you're going to automate the entire
business so that you can free up all the
cash that you need to innovate. And so
she literally went through our business
process by process and she said, "Okay,
what's your role? Your role is to you
upload the videos to YouTube and and you
key tag and you keyword search them."
Great. She built an AI agent that does
the keyword search, the clips. So you
know the clips that I spoke to you about
where I told you that we clip all our
content. That's all. It's an AI. We used
to hire 10 clippers or five clippers. Uh
we now have one and he runs 40 Twitter
accounts and he has one AI tool. He'll
run this interview.
>> We built it. We built it. Um, it learns
how to listen for clips and it clips all
the content and it can actually upload
them directly to Twitter. So, he runs 10
Twitter accounts. Uh, one guy runs 10 10
Twitter accounts. Um, so she automated
the entire business. Literally, uh, the
thumbnail, how we make our thumbnails
now, we you can the it's the system
autogenerates based on on everything
else or you can just draw it on a piece
of paper with a pen. just draw a little
thumbnail and just show it to the AI and
it'll generate that thumbnail for you in
20 seconds. So that took about
20 staff and move and made them two two
or three. So there's two and there's an
overflow guy. Um that was the first
thing that we did. So we we literally
took the entire process of our business.
We looked at the things we were doing
repeatedly and we built AI agents and
and that's that's now running.
Um, we have a thing called the newsroom.
Now, what is the newsroom? It's we have
50 people that are interested in crypto,
including all my researchers. And every
tweet, every article that we read, we
for years, we've actually been copying
and pasting into the newsroom. So, if I
I'll like a tweet from RA and I'll put
it in the newsroom. And and you'll like
a tweet from the Fed and you'll put in
the newsroom and and Bob will like a
tweet from Nvidia and you'll put it in
the newsroom. And for years we've been
doing that like since we started banter
we've been all depositing. So we took an
AI agent and we basically said this is
where we scraped all the data in the
past. Um very simplistically we kind of
said look uh the more recent ones get a
higher score because they means that
they're more relevant to now. The old
ones get a slightly lower score. But
basically what we told the AI agents is
we said tally up how many how many
tweets from each place we recorded based
on that. that's how how likely we are to
want to see the tweet again. And now the
the that whole uh process is is
completely automated, right? So that
there's a bunch of agents that basically
populate [snorts] us with ideas, trading
ideas, alpha, etc., etc. And that that
basically is uh is completely automated.
Um so we basically automated all those
processes. Um I'll give you like stupid
things like we we do interviews like
this. So when I interview a guest,
sometimes I don't know them as well as I
know you. So you know your content I
watch and I know you and I follow you.
But sometimes you get a guest and don't
really know much about him. That process
of getting a document takes me about 30
seconds. I've got an AI agent. It gives
me a background. Who's this person,
where they come from? In fact, it's so
funny because, you know, it's a we we
run the process for everyone. And uh I
just want to see if I've got the
document. If I've got yesterday's
document for cuz you were on my show
yesterday and they sent me
>> You need to hide the bit where he says
he's a bit of a dick.
>> That's the
>> Hold on. Yeah, he's so arrogant. And I
got to actually see I've actually got to
see if I've got it. Uh effectively, I
got I get like a a two minute in two
minutes. I basically know everything I
need to know about you. I get your
latest tweets, your latest views, latest
things that you've said on on latest
YouTube interviews. And so I know that
within four minutes of reading a
document, right? So that that's
basically that. And then when it comes
to valuing tokens, um, so we've
programmed the pipe. In other words,
look for tokens. Look for tokens that
have high buyback pressure, uh, high
buyback pressure, low circulating
supplies, increasing users. I mean,
that's really basic stuff because
everything's available on blockchain and
you can actually start finding it. So to
be honest, the thing that I'm working on
right now with with a couple of the guys
is to try and find to build the perfect
formula for pressure so the AI agent can
tell us. The AI agent, as I said, one of
the the AI agents actually did catch the
arbitum trade very early before people
really caught on how big arbitum is
going to be. When Robin Hood launched,
it basically said, "Hold on, you guys
are missing like there's this pro. We we
we found it at a multiple of five." And
it was like weird. And then we like
double checked the thesis three or four
times and was like hold on a second this
is like a real thesis like and then we
we traded on it and then that trade
yielded us like a 5x return because
we're just so early to the trade because
people didn't pick it up. So again
without AI yeah maybe I would have
caught it but I probably would have
caught it after the run. So yeah, things
like that. I mean, other things other
things which are like um
>> you haven't built a you haven't tried
the trading bot yet where it it just
does takes all of you guys out of the
process because that's the obvious
thing.
>> We've tried it. We've tried it. We've
tried it. We to be honest, we we haven't
really had success to be honest. You
know, you know what is really good what
is really good in blockchain is uh
tracking wallets. So, for example,
tracking team wallets and the minute
that the team wallet having agents that
track w team wallets, the minute a team
wallet starts to move tokens, that
usually has a correlation with price or
so. You look for specific token wallet
movements like I'm not going to mention
the name of the protocol, but I'm
actually watching on my screen here that
a team is moving tokens that they
probably shouldn't be moving, right? And
we've put an AI agent watching every
transaction, watching because sometimes
what they do is they bounce it from one
wallet to a second wallet and then from
a second wallet to a third wallet to to
try and trick people. But we've built a
bunch of a swarm of agents that
basically watch this kind of stuff. So
I'm I'm actually watching one now and I
mean the price has gone down 10% since
we started the show because the team's
actually moving tokens around that they
shouldn't be moving tokens around. So I
I haven't actually dug into it, but I
can see the price going down. I can see
the tokens actually moving. So, and
again, I wouldn't have known that if
there wasn't a Grockbot running here and
telling me exactly what what's going on.
>> Fascinating.
So, Raman, where should people find you?
>> I mean, most people know who you are,
but you know,
>> I'm on Twitter, Cryptoman Run. Uh, I do
a show on Banter, Cryptobanter, and I've
got another channel called Crypto
Insider, which is where I do uh long
form interviews. I think probably
Twitter's the best place because that's
the hub, the hub for everything.
>> That's the easiest place to find you.
>> Otherwise, you can find me in Cape Town.
and you can come and visit me in Cape
Town.
>> Yeah, we'll see you or I'll see you in
Singapore and I'll see you in
Johannesburg and I'll see you in Cape
Town.
>> I'll see you somewhere. All right, my
friend. Good to see you and uh see you
soon.
>> Chat soon, man.
>> This episode is brought to you by Pith.
Pith Network is the fastest growing
financial data company [music] today.
Trusted by Fidelity Investments, the US
Department of Commerce, Revolute,
Kelshi, Jane Street, Coinbase, and many
more. They provide real time financial
market data across over 3,000 [music]
equities, commodities, crypto, FX,
rates, and again a lot more. They're the
first and largest provider of 24/7
financial indices and offer the widest
array of market data for [music] the
lowest cost. So go to pith.network to
take advantage of their free trial.
Token 2049 Singapore, the world's
largest crypto event, returns to [music]
Marina Bay Sands on the 7th of 8th of
October. On stage will be myself, Jeff
Yan from Hyperlquid, Shane Copam from
Poly Market, [music] and the Real Vision
community gets 10% off tickets. Claim
yours using the link below. See you
there. So, you obviously like this video
enough that you've got to the end.
That's quite a big task, but listen, do
me a favor. Hit the like and subscribe
button and also check out what videos
next because I think you'll love it. But
if you want even more, and when I'm
talking more, I'm talking about
memberergenerated ideas, incredible
alpha research, everything there to help
you in your journey, just head to
realton.com/join
for the best financial intelligence out
there and the pure alpha that's within
the platform.